

# PRASHANT DUBEY

# **Mechanical Design Engineer**

Ph: +91-9457258299

Email: <u>prashantdubey96@gmail.com</u> Silvassa – 396230, D&NH, INDIA

## **SYNOPSIS**

A Professional with total experience of 4 years in product Design & development, well conversant with different manufacturing processes and its applications with expertise in 2D and 3D components modeling, Drafting, Detailing using CAD Tools like Solidworks 2020, Autocad 2D, UG NX 12.0, Catia V5.

Currently seeking another opportunity for growth of my professional career.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Mechanical Design Engineer**

EPAVO ELECTRICALS (RR WIRES)- Dadra, D&H

(March 2021 - Till Now)

### Role & Responsibilities:-

- o 3D modeling and rendering work for new and existing part in solid works.
- o 3D designing & execution for new and existing product development in solid works.
- o BOM preparation for new or existing product.
- Preparing 3D Prototypes through 3D printing.
- o Co-ordination with Machine shop and Assembly line for R&D purpose.
- Vendor assessment & throughout coordination regarding project.
- o Technical specification & content, SOPs, User Manuals, Data-Sheets preparation.
- Experienced VA/VE activities with the help marketing team.

#### **Mechanical Design Engineer**

DO WELL MOULDS- Vapi

(May 2020 - Dec 2020)

#### **Role & Responsibilities:-**

- o Designed, managed, and lead design reviews for new products and processes from concept through full production.
- o Produced 3D drawings and designs using AutoCAD 2D.
- o Create assembly drawings, including detail drawings for machining.
- Created solid models and assemblies, containing numerous parts made of injection molded plastic, blow moulding plastic and stretch moulds.

## **Mechanical Design Engineer**

(Jan 2019 – May 2020)

Altis Industries Pvt. Ltd. – Indore

#### **Role & Responsibilities:-**

- Designing and Detailing of steel structure using Solidworks.
- Preparing design criteria, engineering calculations, technical specifications, data sheets and reports, coordination of structural design work.
- o Preparing 3D samples for sheet metal enclosures in Nx.
- Surface modeling for customized panels using Nx.

### **EDUCATION**

Skill-Lync - Autonomous

Design Masters | Percentile – 92%

Maharshi Dayanand University – MDU 2015-2018

B.Tech – Mechanical Engineering | Percentile – 66.77%

Rustam Ji Institute of Technology (RJIT) – RGPV 2012-2015

Diploma – Mechanical Engineering | Percentile – 70.50%

CBSE 2012

High school – Math, Science | CGPA – 9.0

### **INTERNSHIP**

**Production Trainee** (Jan 2018 – May 2018)

Gabriel India Ltd. – Gurgaon

# Role & Responsibilities:-

Line balancing according to take time.

- Utilization of resources to get Maximum output
- o Training on OEE, KAIZEN, POKA-YOKE system for reducing rejection per shift.
- o Responsible for overall Production in the respective shift.
- o Provide kaizen to Reduce Cycle Time for Some Machine to Improve Production.
- o To maintain 5'S on shop Floor & Reduce the Rejection and follow plant ethics.
- Responsible for day to day planning and Production with better utilization of manpower according to skill matrix and resources.

### **TOOLS**

- Solidworks
   MS Office
- o Catia
- o UG NX
- Autocad
- Simplify 3D

### **SKILLS**

- o 3D Modelling
- Surface Modelling
- Drafting
- o Engineering Drawing
- Machine Drawing
- Rendering

- Plastic Design
- Injection Molding
- o Fabrication
- o GD&T
- Sheet Metal Design
- 3D Printing

### PERSONAL DETAILS

Known Languages: English, Hindi

Gender: Male Date Of Birth: 11 Nov 1996

Marital Status: Married Permanent Address: T-98, Ward- Azadnagar, Post-

Ajitmal, Dist- Auraiya, U.P. - 206121

Current Address: Saket Complex, Silvassa, Dadra &

Nagar Haveli, - 396230